<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Guitar</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/</link><description>Recent content on Guitar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Expensive amplifier, cheap guitar...</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/expensive-amplifier-cheap-guitar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/expensive-amplifier-cheap-guitar/</guid><description>Photo by Clem Onojeghuo from Pexels.
I grew up swearing by this ethos. If I had a good amp, it would pretty much mask anything, old strings, a rubbish guitar made of driftwood, bad technique…okay, not so much, but I’ll stand by the guitar part.
Fact is, a cheap guitar will sound fairly decent on a good amp. A good guitar will sound absolutely awful on a cheap amp.</description></item><item><title>I don't like the sound of a guitar amplifier without a microphone any more!</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/i-dont-like-the-sound-of-a-guitar-amplifier-without-a-microphone-any-more/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/i-dont-like-the-sound-of-a-guitar-amplifier-without-a-microphone-any-more/</guid><description>Back in January 2019 NAMM I’d heard about the brand new Marshall JCM800 SC20H Studio head, but thought nothing of it as I was still in full flow, Kemper-loving heaven. The Kemper had killed my “GAS” for amplifiers successfully for the last 12 months or so, but recently, my passion for amps has bitten me, with a vengeance.
I had a brief flirt with amps back in January 2019, but it didn’t amount to much as ultimately, the amp in question didn’t quite live up to my expectations and the Kemper trumped it in terms of versatility.</description></item><item><title>Kemper owner for a year and why I’m returning to valves in 2019</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/kemper-owner-for-a-year-and-why-im-returning-to-valves-in-2019/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/kemper-owner-for-a-year-and-why-im-returning-to-valves-in-2019/</guid><description>The paralysing limitations of having access to every guitar amplifier in the world.
I admit, the last few months have been a bit of a struggle with the Kemper. Not because it sounds anything less than superb, but simply because the profiles aren’t versatile enough once I’ve found &amp;lsquo;the one’.
Once I’ve settled on a profile, I’m stuck with it because no other profile comes close. That makes me feel a little uneasy as I’d like to feel a bit more freedom than that.</description></item><item><title>Building my dream guitar rig. 2018: Kemper Profiler</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/building-my-dream-guitar-rig-2018-kemper-profiler/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/building-my-dream-guitar-rig-2018-kemper-profiler/</guid><description>After seeing a video comparing the Axe FX III and the Kemper (that has unfortunately now been deleted by its maker, Camilo Velandia— an Axe FX III owner) which I spoke about in my previous post, “One year later with the Fractal Axe FX II XL, was it a keeper in 2018?”, my first instinct was to try the Kemper in the interim, whilst I wait for the Axe FX III to arrive in the country.</description></item><item><title>One year later with the Fractal Axe FX II XL, was it a keeper in 2018?</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/one-year-later-with-the-fractal-axe-fx-ii-xl-was-it-a-keeper-in-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/one-year-later-with-the-fractal-axe-fx-ii-xl-was-it-a-keeper-in-2018/</guid><description>In March 2017 I made the massive leap to a fully digital guitar rig. I can now document my year long journey from Axe FX newbie to massive digital convert.
Big investment I had to sell a lot of my old analog gear, including my amp and pedals, to get back some of the money I spent on the Axe FX II XL. It was a huge make or break investment of time, money and loss; of things I’d come to cherish.</description></item><item><title>Building my dream guitar rig. 2017: Fractal Axe FX II XL</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/building-my-dream-guitar-rig-2017-fractal-axe-fx-ii-xl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/building-my-dream-guitar-rig-2017-fractal-axe-fx-ii-xl/</guid><description>Sometimes, you just need to accept the facts.
[Disclaimer: this is an old article and explains my thoughts about the Fractal Axe FX II XL in 2017]
So, after finally coming to a place where I could accept that I had most of the basic tones covered, why did I still want more? Why was I still missing my Mesa? Why did I suddenly feel the urge to buy a Plexi style amplifier?</description></item><item><title>Built my dream guitar rig and now I'm selling it. Part 2: The dream rig 2017</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/built-my-dream-guitar-rig-part-2-the-dream-rig-2017/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/built-my-dream-guitar-rig-part-2-the-dream-rig-2017/</guid><description>The culmination of 5+ years of building my dream rig and the absolute pinnacle of what I think are my favourite sounds from these little stop boxes - this is my homage.
The gear So, after years of searching for the ultimate stomp box — here’s my list…
The amplifier I’ve had many amplifiers over the years. It’s perhaps a little ironic and always makes me laugh that I started with a Laney, a ‘Linebacker’ 30w solid state that was given to me by a friend who also gave me my first electric guitar, and now I have the immense 20w tube driven Laney Lionheart — my favourite amp of all time.</description></item><item><title>Built my dream guitar rig and now I'm selling it. Part 1</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/built-my-dream-guitar-rig-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/built-my-dream-guitar-rig-part-1/</guid><description>Remember the days when it was all about the chase? You’d invest so much time into a relationship with the aim of finally being with the person of your dreams. Then one day, you realise you enjoyed the chase a little more than the relationship.
I’ve spent the last five years amassing the most incredible lineup of pedals, the tools that help define and sculpt my tone…my sound. I’ve got a beautiful amplifier, and four guitars that some could only dream of.</description></item><item><title>Reactive load and Impulse Response (IR) speaker cabinet simulation question and answer</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/reactive-load-and-impulse-response-speaker-cabinet-simulation-question-and-answer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/reactive-load-and-impulse-response-speaker-cabinet-simulation-question-and-answer/</guid><description>I had a lot of questions after my first blog post — “How to get a great guitar tone at any volume”. Here’s a few and I’ll add more over time. Feel free to ask more questions in the comments.
What if I have an amp/speaker combo, not just an amplifier head? You can still use a reactive load box with it. Unplug the internal speaker and go straight into the load box.</description></item><item><title>How to get a great guitar tone at any volume</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/how-to-get-a-great-guitar-tone-at-any-volume/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/how-to-get-a-great-guitar-tone-at-any-volume/</guid><description>Stereo with one amp, wet/dry, no microphones, any speaker you can think of, consistent beautiful tone, low volume…a guitarists dream!
It’s always been a passion of mine to be able to hear what my guitar sounds like in stereo. I bought my first stereo effects pedal, a DOD FX747 Supersonic Flanger way back in 2000. Since then, I’ve been on a mission to find a good stereo solution that wouldn’t involve two separate amps.</description></item></channel></rss>