<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>building my dream guitar rig on Guitar</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/tags/building-my-dream-guitar-rig/</link><description>Recent content in building my dream guitar rig on Guitar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/tags/building-my-dream-guitar-rig/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why I returned to real guitar amplifiers in 2020 after using Kemper and Axe FX</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/why-i-returned-to-real-guitar-amplifiers-in-2020-after-using-kemper-and-axe-fx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/why-i-returned-to-real-guitar-amplifiers-in-2020-after-using-kemper-and-axe-fx/</guid><description>Two years of using digital amps lead me back to the real thing.
The last year (2019) has been a massive overhaul for me, in terms of gear. I started the year with a Kemper Profiler and many of you will know that I have raved about that piece of kit for the best part of 18 months now. It’s a game changer. However, I missed the flexibility of real amps and pedals at my fingertips.</description></item><item><title>Kemper owner for a year and why I’m returning to valves in 2019</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/kemper-owner-for-a-year-and-why-im-returning-to-valves-in-2019/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/kemper-owner-for-a-year-and-why-im-returning-to-valves-in-2019/</guid><description>The paralysing limitations of having access to every guitar amplifier in the world.
I admit, the last few months have been a bit of a struggle with the Kemper. Not because it sounds anything less than superb, but simply because the profiles aren’t versatile enough once I’ve found &amp;lsquo;the one’.
Once I’ve settled on a profile, I’m stuck with it because no other profile comes close. That makes me feel a little uneasy as I’d like to feel a bit more freedom than that.</description></item><item><title>Building my dream guitar rig. 2018: Kemper Profiler</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/building-my-dream-guitar-rig-2018-kemper-profiler/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/building-my-dream-guitar-rig-2018-kemper-profiler/</guid><description>After seeing a video comparing the Axe FX III and the Kemper (that has unfortunately now been deleted by its maker, Camilo Velandia— an Axe FX III owner) which I spoke about in my previous post, “One year later with the Fractal Axe FX II XL, was it a keeper in 2018?”, my first instinct was to try the Kemper in the interim, whilst I wait for the Axe FX III to arrive in the country.</description></item><item><title>One year later with the Fractal Axe FX II XL, was it a keeper in 2018?</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/one-year-later-with-the-fractal-axe-fx-ii-xl-was-it-a-keeper-in-2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/one-year-later-with-the-fractal-axe-fx-ii-xl-was-it-a-keeper-in-2018/</guid><description>In March 2017 I made the massive leap to a fully digital guitar rig. I can now document my year long journey from Axe FX newbie to massive digital convert.
Big investment I had to sell a lot of my old analog gear, including my amp and pedals, to get back some of the money I spent on the Axe FX II XL. It was a huge make or break investment of time, money and loss; of things I’d come to cherish.</description></item></channel></rss>