<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Guitar</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Guitar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building my dream guitar rig.  2017: Fractal Axe FX II XL</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/building-my-dream-guitar-rig-2017-fractal-axe-fx-ii-xl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/building-my-dream-guitar-rig-2017-fractal-axe-fx-ii-xl/</guid><description>Sometimes, you just need to accept the facts.
[Disclaimer: this is an old article and explains my thoughts about the Fractal Axe FX II XL in 2017]
So, after finally coming to a place where I could accept that I had most of the basic tones covered, why did I still want more? Why was I still missing my Mesa? Why did I suddenly feel the urge to buy a Plexi style amplifier?</description></item><item><title>Built my dream guitar rig and now I'm selling it. Part 2: The dream rig 2017</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/built-my-dream-guitar-rig-part-2-the-dream-rig-2017/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/built-my-dream-guitar-rig-part-2-the-dream-rig-2017/</guid><description>The culmination of 5+ years of building my dream rig and the absolute pinnacle of what I think are my favourite sounds from these little stop boxes - this is my homage.
The gear So, after years of searching for the ultimate stomp box — here’s my list…
The amplifier I’ve had many amplifiers over the years. It’s perhaps a little ironic and always makes me laugh that I started with a Laney, a ‘Linebacker’ 30w solid state that was given to me by a friend who also gave me my first electric guitar, and now I have the immense 20w tube driven Laney Lionheart — my favourite amp of all time.</description></item><item><title>Built my dream guitar rig and now I'm selling it. Part 1</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/built-my-dream-guitar-rig-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/built-my-dream-guitar-rig-part-1/</guid><description>Remember the days when it was all about the chase? You’d invest so much time into a relationship with the aim of finally being with the person of your dreams. Then one day, you realise you enjoyed the chase a little more than the relationship.
I’ve spent the last five years amassing the most incredible lineup of pedals, the tools that help define and sculpt my tone…my sound. I’ve got a beautiful amplifier, and four guitars that some could only dream of.</description></item><item><title>Reactive load and Impulse Response (IR) speaker cabinet simulation question and answer</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/reactive-load-and-impulse-response-speaker-cabinet-simulation-question-and-answer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/reactive-load-and-impulse-response-speaker-cabinet-simulation-question-and-answer/</guid><description>I had a lot of questions after my first blog post — “How to get a great guitar tone at any volume”. Here’s a few and I’ll add more over time. Feel free to ask more questions in the comments.
What if I have an amp/speaker combo, not just an amplifier head? You can still use a reactive load box with it. Unplug the internal speaker and go straight into the load box.</description></item><item><title>How to get a great guitar tone at any volume</title><link>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/how-to-get-a-great-guitar-tone-at-any-volume/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanthomas83.github.io/guitar/how-to-get-a-great-guitar-tone-at-any-volume/</guid><description>Stereo with one amp, wet/dry, no microphones, any speaker you can think of, consistent beautiful tone, low volume…a guitarists dream!
It’s always been a passion of mine to be able to hear what my guitar sounds like in stereo. I bought my first stereo effects pedal, a DOD FX747 Supersonic Flanger way back in 2000. Since then, I’ve been on a mission to find a good stereo solution that wouldn’t involve two separate amps.</description></item></channel></rss>